准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
垃圾宝宝
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
欢迎来到酷乐湖
来酷乐湖
By the goo
来到那酷乐湖
By the googly-goo
你我泡进酷乐湖
Me and you in the goo
爽玩厚实的糊糊
It's as chunky as stew
这地方正好
The perfect spot
不好意思  先生
Excuse me, sir
这是你的吗
Is this yours?
再也不是了
Not anymore
你们几位小朋友掉了
You kids dropped
东西
something
好吧  我去把它们丢掉
Okay, I'll dispose of them
等等
Wait
回来  包装纸
Come back, wrapper
抱歉
Sorry
他刚说抱歉
Sorry, he says
不好意思
Pardon me
对不起
My fault
贻贝海滩
抱歉抱歉
Sorry, sorry
是我的错
Mea culpa
是我不好
My bad
请接受我最诚挚的道歉
Please accept my sincerest apologies
两百声哎呀后
逮到了
Gotcha
是我干的吗
Did I do that?
小包装纸  看来
Well, little wrapper, it looks like
今天我有得忙了
I've got a busy day ahead of me
每一位居民都有义务
Every citizen must do their part
保持海滩干净整洁无垃圾
to keep our beaches debris-free
垃圾  垃圾
Trash, trash
到处是垃圾
Everywhere trash
各种废料都捡起
Picking up flotsam and jetsam
海绵宝宝是我名
SpongeBob's the name
捡起垃圾我最行
And litter's my game
只要你有垃圾  我就会去收
So if you got garbage I'll get some
只要你有垃圾  他就会去收
So if ya got garbage he'll get some
我就不能好好晒日光浴
Can't a guy sunbathe
不被长矛扎屁股吗
without getting a spear in the tuchus?
抱歉  痞老板
Sorry, Plankton
从我余光看去
From the corner of my eye
你就跟个肮脏的陈年腌椰菜似的
you looked like a dirty old pickle
千万不要吃浮游生物
Do not eat the plankton
虽然他看着好吃  但他不是腌椰菜
He may look delicious, but he is not a pickle
不是腌椰菜吗
Not a pickle?
真是的  我可是专门来这吃腌椰菜的
Aw man, I was only here for the pickles
所以我才会特地来海滩
That's why I even came to the beach
天啊
Oh boy
要是一直用这垃圾杆
If I keep using this trash picker
肯定得清理一整个星期
I'll be here all week
有了
I know
来把它设成超级吸沙模式
I'll set it to Super-Sand-Suction
烫到脚了
Hot foot
烫烫烫烫烫
Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot
起码全都干净了
Well, at least it's all clean
吧
I guess
该回家去了  垃圾桶
Time to head home, Canny
晒得挺黑
Sweet tans
我感应到了垃圾
My trashy sense is tingling
有个乱扔垃圾的海霸王
A litterbugging Bubble Bass
看来我在这里的任务还没结束呢
Looks like my job here's not done after all
各位朋友  各位农夫
Friends, yeomen
各位同胞
country fish
请你们把垃圾给我
Lend me your litter
好
Yeah
吁  马儿慢点
Whoa, horsie
裤头村
农贸市场
鲜花
Flowers
糖果
Candy
这是我这辈子跑得最远的一次
This is the most I've ever run in my life
都让一下
Move out of the way
这应该会很有料
This should be delicious
对不起  史赖皮
I'm sorry, Slappy
不对
Oh, no
我才遗憾
I am sorry
我本来还在期待更惨的呢
I was hoping for much worse
万岁
Hurray
好了
There
最后一点也清完了
That's the last of it
你们可以走了
You're good to go
感谢你造成了这么场万分愉快的车祸
Thank you for a most pleasurable traffic accident
看看多么干净啊
Look how clean
酷乐湖上到处一点垃圾都没有
Not a single piece of trash anywhere on Goo Lagoon
我明明把整个镇子清理干净了
I thought I cleaned up this town
看来我必须
Looks like I'll have to
把你连同其他垃圾一起丢进去了
toss you in with the rest of the rubbish
一定是起风了
Must be windy
这里一定是斜坡
And I must be on a hill
你的闪避技巧是很强
Your evasive moves are impressive
但是看招
But behold
古怪风车术
Wacky Windmill-Style
必须得用我的独门秘技
I'll have to use a technique that's specific to me
我们海绵最熟悉的就是洞
If there's one thing us sponges know, it's holes
对  那可真是个好洞啊
Yep, that's a mighty fine hole
你可以靠近一点
Y'all can come closer
不是所有人都能领略大洞之美
It's not everyone that can appreciate
a good-looking hole
既要高雅又要有品味
It takes taste and sophistication
来  我后退一步
Here, I'll just step back
我只是想清理裤头村而已
Gee, all I wanted to do was clean up Bikini Bottom
做点好事
Do something nice
做一点点的善事
Something b-b-beautiful
可我失败了
But I failed
失败了
Failed
我是个废物
I'm a failure
抓到了
Gotcha
清洁工硬挤眼泪的老套路都能骗到你
Fell for the old tears-of-a-trash-man routine
把你放进我口袋里好好保管
I'll just put you in my pocket for safekeeping
我口袋一定是破了个洞
I must have a hole in my pocket
我是个无情又干净的垃圾清理机器
I am a mean, clean, trash machine
感谢你  垃圾
I thank you, trash
让我此次猎捕极具挑战
for a most challenging hunt
以及感谢你的牺牲
And for sacrificing your life
由此我才能清理这片
so I may make clean this
满是垃圾的土地
littered land
好  该来刺你了
Okay, time to stab you
垃圾跳走了
Leapin' litter
游戏还没完呢
The game is still afoot
我发誓过会报复海绵宝宝的
I swore I'd get back at SpongeBob
而最好的报复方式
And what better way
就是用捡不起来的垃圾逼疯他
than driving ol' sanitation boy crazy
with an un-pickable piece of trash?
更何况
Besides
我的小屁屁还在疼着呢
my wittle tushy still hurts
快来爸爸这儿  垃圾宝宝
Come to papa, TrashPants
什么
Wha?
它这是在进化吗
It's evolving?
撑住  手指头
Hang on, fingers
我们尽力了
We're trying
我另一瓣屁股
My other cheek
谁在说话
Who said that?
给我放手  你这捡垃圾的伪君子
Get off, you garbage-picking goody-goody geek
不放手是吧
Not lettin' go, eh?
那就来转转
Let's take a spin
还好不会再有什么意外了
Hopefully there aren't any more surprises
我不会放手的
I won't let go
休想这么容易就摆脱我
You won't get rid of me that easy
我虽然倒下了  但还没出局
I'm down, but not out
放手  海绵宝宝
Get off, SpongeBob
酷乐湖
孔雀鱼高尔夫
WH2O电台
悦耳金枪鱼之家
自2006起
专门播放追逐音乐
完了
No
这个垃圾没油了
This piece of trash just ran out of gas
痞老板
Plankton?
难道是你
Were you--
对  一直都是我
Yes, it was me all along
还能有谁
Who else?
乱扔垃圾的
Litterbugs
你们两个各罚一百块
A hundred dollar fine for the both of you
还得负责给这片海滩的垃圾都捡干净
And you're picking up every piece of trash on this beach
一直捡到年底
for the rest of the year
你又害得我们碰上烂摊子了
Well, this is another fine mess you've gotten us into
蟹堡食堂
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
整理账单可太无聊了
Filing bills is so boring
终于有点正事做了
Finally, a little action
这里是蟹堡王  蟹黄堡之家
You've reached the Krusty Krab, home of the Krabby Patty
我是店长蟹老板
Mr. Krabs, proprietor, speaking
老爸
Daddy
珍珍女儿好
Hiya, Pearly-girl
怎么了
What's going on?
老爸
Daddy
我有个天大的好消息
I have wonderful news
学校里的食堂大妈  莱诺
The school lunch lady, Lenore
今早掉进工业用蛋糕搅拌机里了
fell into the industrial cake mixer this morning
现在伤得可重了
and now she's horribly injured
那还
That's
算好消息吗
wonderful?
对啊
It is
因为我跟大家说
Because I told everyone
你会来做蟹黄堡给大家当午餐
that you would come and serve Krabby Patties for lunch
这下我就会是全校最酷的女生了
Now I'm the coolest girl in school
万岁
Hooray
珍珍  你要知道
Pearl, you know
我可不怎么喜欢自己当年的高中经历
I didn't exactly love me last go-around in high school
参与奖
尤金蟹
羽毛球初级校队
拜托了  老爸
Please, Daddy, please
想想你能引来多少新客人
Think of all the new customers you could make
新客人吗
New customers?
我就喜欢早早树立品牌忠诚度
I like building brand loyalty early
好  我这就去
Okay, I'll do it
好耶
Yippee
谢了  老爸
Thanks, Daddy
动作快一点  午餐时间要到了
And hurry up, it's almost lunchtime
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward
什么事  蟹老板
Yes, sir, Mr. Krabs?
带上锅铲  小子
Grab your spatul-er, boy-o
我们要回高中
We're headin' back to high school
去掌管食堂
to man the cafeteri-er
不知道我曾经的音乐老师还在不在
I wonder if my old music teacher is still there
我可以突然出现
I could pop in
给小朋友们启发一点音乐灵感
and give the kids a little musical inspiration
你还是别跟过来了  章鱼哥先生
You're not comin' with, Mr. Squidward
我需要有人留在这掌舵看店
I need someone manning the helm here
出发了  小子
Let's roll, boy-o
遵命  蟹老板
Aye-aye, Mr. Krabs
看管好蟹堡王的事
Keep an eye on things
我们马上回来
We'll be back soon
果不其然
Typical
至少今天没什么生意
At least it's a slow day
该来睡个美容觉了
Time to get some beauty rest
高中
是母校
The ol' alma mater
绝绝对对无一例外最后重申
"Absolutely, without exception, and for the final time
泡泡独轮车严禁入校园
bubble unicycles are strictly
prohibited on school grounds"
一定是新规定
That must be new
老爸好
Hi, Daddy
真高兴你来了
Glad you're here
往那边走就是食堂
Cafeteria's that way
食堂
谢谢你帮我酷一把
Thanks for making me cool
走吧  小子
Let's go, boy-o
这里比想象中还要有点压抑  蟹老板
This is slightly more grim than expected, Mr. Krabs
好了
All right
起来  你们这些懒鱼
get up, you lazy flounders
没排好队就不准吃饭
No one eats until you form an orderly line
这就是规定
That's the rules
你好
Hello there
谁插队
Who's cuttin' in my line?
我们是新来的食堂员工
We're the new kitchen crew
你一定就是食堂大妈莱诺吧
And you must be Lunch Lady Lenore
没想到你还在
Didn't think you'd be here
我掌管这家食堂已经40年了
I've run this cafeteria for 40 years
以为我被搅拌机弄残废就不干了吗
You think I'm gonna
let a little horrific mangling keep me away?
给我回岗位上去
Now get to your stations
遵命
Yes, ma'am
好耶  开始做蟹黄堡吧
Oh boy, time to get cooking
我说你呢
You there
你干什么
What are you doing?
我只是在做准备  要煎肉饼做蟹黄堡
I'm just getting ready to grill up some Krabby Patties
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patties?
我的食堂严禁外带食物
No outside food in my cafeteria
只许吃批准入内的食物
Approved foods only
这就是规定
That's the rules
我可不想违反规定
Well, I'd hate to be a rule-breaker
来看小朋友们今天都吃什么
Let's see what the kids are gettin' today
菜单
煮海带
Boiled kelp?
煮肉糕
Boiled loaf?
煮蛋糕
Boiled cake?
一听就难吃
That sounds awful
不过要是我肉糕做得够好吃的话
Although, if I make the meatloaf tasty enough
食物用不着你来做
You don't cook the food
食品仓库早都预制好料理包送来了
It's delivered in boiling bags
from the food depository
快去煮
Now get to boiling
快啊  老头子
Come on, old man
珍珍答应过我们有蟹黄堡吃的
Pearl promised us Krabby Patties
对
Yeah
大家先冷静
Calm down, everyone
吃的随时都会送到大家手上
You'll be getting served any minute now
等我的厨子送上你们的蟹黄堡就行了
as soon as me cook delivers up yer Krabby Patties
海绵宝宝  快点
SpongeBob, hurry up
上菜了
Order up
这是什么  小子
What is this, boy-o?
船上禁闭室里的食物卖相都比这好
I've seen tastier lookin' meals in the brig
我的蟹黄堡哪去了
Where's all my Krabby Patties?
很抱歉
I'm so sorry
都是规定
It's the rules
给我东西吃
Feed me
那不是蟹黄堡
That isn't a Krabby Patty
太没味道了
So flavorless
蟹老板  我不能就这样子工作
Mr. Krabs, I can't work like this
没调料的食物违背了煎炸厨师的原则
Unseasoned food goes against the fry cook's code
所以
So
还好我带来了自己私藏的香辛料
Good thing I brought my secret stash
of herbs and spices
这般美味  就好像
The deliciousness is, like
在激起我年轻的心
stimulating my young mind
风味会害小孩子无法无天
Flavor causes unruly children
所以得禁止
It is forbidden
给我回去煮料理包
Now back to boiling bags
还有你
And you
回去丢垃圾给小孩子吃
Back to slinging slop
不准激励小孩子
And no inspiring the children
这是规定
It's the rules
对  我爸的蟹黄堡
Yeah, my dad's Krabby Patties
是全裤头村最美味的食物
are the tastiest food in town
这一定会是最棒的午餐
This is gonna be the best lunch ever
珍珍  这是在开玩笑吗
Pearl, is this some kind of a joke?
老爸
Daddy
搞什么鬼
What's the deal?
你怎么没给大家做蟹黄堡
Why aren't you serving Krabby Patties
我明明都答应过大家了
like I promised everyone?
我只能做这坨垃圾给大家吃
I can't serve nothin' but this slop
那个食堂大妈盯得可紧了
while that lunch lady is watchin'
想吃蟹黄堡  就得引开她注意力
If you want patties, we need a distraction
既能让她入迷  又微妙到不易察觉
Something engrossing, but, you know, subtle
拜托
Please
我最大的特点就是微妙
Subtle is my middle name
目光朝我这边放
Keep on looking straight at me
不用看别的地方
There's nothing else you need to see
现在这又是干嘛
What's all this now?
引开你的注意力  万岁
D-I-S, T-R-A, C-T-I-O-N, hooray
小子  机会来了
Alright, boy-o, now's our chance
快利用这些小孩子树立品牌忠诚度
to build some brand loyalty with these brats
上蟹黄堡吧
Bring on the patties
上菜了
Order up
后边又是怎么了
What's going on out there?
注
Pay
意
Attention
注意我
Pay me attention
外带食物
Outside food?
快乐的小孩子
Happy children?
违反规定了
It's against the rules
蟹黄堡给我
Gimme those patties
休想
I don't think so
完了
Oh no
我的人气
My popularity
我恨这坨垃圾
I hate this slop
食物大战
Food fight?
这种事违反规定了
That's against the rules
一份食堂大妈特餐
One lunch lady special
上菜了
Order up
你们都违反了
You're all breaking the--
我做了这么多年的学校食堂午餐
All those years of cooking school lunches
都忘了风味竟能有如此之乐趣
made me forget how fun flavor can be
谢了  海绵宝宝
Thank ya, SpongeBob
只是在尽煎炸厨师的责任  女士
Just doing a fry cook's duty, ma'am
听好了  小朋友
Listen up, children
大家上校车
Everyone on the buses
我们要去蟹堡王做校外教学
We're taking a field trip to the Krusty Krab
食堂大妈能组织校外教学吗
Can a lunch lady do that?
管他呢
Who cares?
我要来个蟹黄堡
I want a Krabby Patty
我的噩梦总算结束了
Finally, my nightmare is over
食物大战
Food fight
这也太强了
This rules
你要我干嘛
What do you want me to do?
什么都不用干  小子
Not a thing, boy-o
他们丢得越多  就买得越多
The more they throw, the more they buy
进厨房里去  多做点弹药出来
Now get in that kitchen and grill up more ammunition
遵命  老板
Sir, yes, sir
弹药来了
Incoming